CALICHE OROZCO

Front-end Software Developer

Q	Veracruz, Ver
	info@calicheorozco.com
	LinkedIn

+52 2293450020
Github
Portafolio

SUMMARY

Middle Front-End developer with two years of experience building responsive web design and mobile apps completely responsive, and intuitive for users at startups. Proficient with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, plus modern libraries and frameworks, with a specific focus on React Js.

SKILLS

✓ Leadership
 ✓ Teaching
 ✓ Teamwork player
 ✓ Good Listener
 ✓ Decision making
 ✓ Teaching
 ✓ Fast learning

Programming languages Frameworks

Javascript React js
HTML Flask
CSS
Python

Libraries

Java

✓ Tailwind CSS
 ✓ React Query
 ✓ Bootstrap
 ✓ GraphQL
 ✓ Openpyxl
 ✓ Next js
 ✓ TypeScript
 ✓ Chart js

LANGUAGES

I am bilingual as I perform efficiently in both English and Spanish.

Spanish: Native Language English: Advance Level

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Web Developer

Date Started – Date Ended

BEDU, Mexico City, CDMX

12/2021 - 06/2022

- Built websites with React and TailwindCSS.
- Collaborated with the UX/UI design teams to improve the website, increasing the speed of the site by 50%.
- Worked with product and backend teams to create different web products.
- Participated in product releases and code reviews with 3 Senior developers and team leads.
- Great work ethic and attention to detail.
- Assisted in building 100% reusable code and libraries for future use.

Different frontend activities were assigned, which I solved with technologies such as Next JS, TypeScript, React-hook-form, Editor.js, Node.js, ReactQuery, GraphQL, etc.

Web Developer Apprenticeship

Date Started - Date Ended

Name: Caliche Orozco

07/2021 - 12/2021

SCIO Consulting, Michoacán, Michoacán

- Knowledge of UX/UI best practices.
- Learned and applied scrum methodology.
- Worked with product teams on new launches.
- Optimized application for maximum speed and scalability.
- Worked on the technical debts and reduced by 30%.

Front-end Developer Internship

Date Started - Date Ended

Logiety, Veracruz, Veracruz

02/2021 - 12/2021

- Built landing pages with React and CSS.
- Creation of Templates in Openpyxl reduced the time for the filling of forms in 90%.
- Built CSS effects improving the interaction between the clients and the website.
- Developed new features.

EDUCATION

Computer Systems Engineer

Veracruz Technological Institute

VOLUNTEERING

Help Newcomers and promoter of Latino America culture

Date Started - Date Ended

Moncton, New Brunswick, Canada

07/2022 - Currently

Helping newcomers from Latino America in Moncton to integrate with the community of New Brunswick and share Latino America culture in event as Mosaiq Moncton Festival 2022 with the nonprofit organization Hola New Brunswick.

IT culture coordinator and promoter

Date Started - Date Ended

Veracruz, Mexico

09/2017 - 07/2021

Coordinate event such as Talent Nights Veracruz 2017-2019, Arduino Day Veracruz 2018-2019, Hacker Day 2019, Tecnovation Challange Veracruz, Technological Meetups Veracruz, etc.

Pro sustainability culture coordinator and promoter

Date Started - Date Ended

Veracruz, Mexico

09/2017 - 01/2022

Founder and organizer of activities for sustainable development such as Beach cleaning, Support for marginalized communities, Reforestation of parks, Visits to hospitals, Collection of recyclable material, etc.